Guide to the Washington Square News RG.39.178
New York University Archives
Washington Square News
1973-2017
New York University Archives
RG.39.178
74 Linear Feet in 42 flat boxes, 9 reels of microfilm, and 51 bound volumes
This collection contains issues from the student newspaper the Washington Square News (established as the Washington Square Daily News), dating from 1973 to 2017. This newspaper documents life at NYU, local and national news, campus living, and student clubs. The collection is extensive but not comprehensive, there may be some issues that were published but are not included in this collection. This collection includes issues in their original print format as well as microfilmed copies. Some issues are bound.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
Newspapers are arranged chronologically.
Historical Note
New York University has had many student newspapers with many different names since its founding. The Heights campus and the Washington Square campus had separate student newspapers until 1973 when the Heights campus was closed. The Washington Square News was first published in the fall of 1973, and was preceded by the Washington Square Journal. Originally titled the Washington Square Daily News, the newspaper shortened its title in the fall of 1974. The newspaper is still being published as of 2019.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains issues from the student newspaper the Washington Square News (established as the Washington Square Daily News), dating from 1973 to 2017. This newspaper documents life at NYU, local and national news, campus living, and student clubs. This collection also contains Washington Square News's arts and culture publication, The Village Angle Magazine, dating from 1983 to 1988. The collection is extensive but not comprehensive, there may be some issues that were published but are not included in this collection. This collection includes issues in their original print format as well as microfilmed copies. Some issues are bound.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Researchers must consult microfilm copies for issues published between 1973 and 1987 due to the fragility of the original newspapers.
College student newspapers and periodicals.; Student activities.
- Microfilm copies
  - Washington Square Daily News, September 1973-May 1974 (Box Microfilm 6, Reel 5056)
  - Washington Square News, September 1974-May 1976 (Box Microfilm 6, Reel 5057)
  - Washington Square News, September 1976-May 1978 (Box Microfilm 6, Reel 5058)
  - Washington Square News, September 1978-May 1980 (Box Microfilm 6, Reel 5059)
  - Washington Square News, September 1980-May 1982 (Box Microfilm 6, Reel 5060)
  - Washington Square News, September 1982-April 1984 (Box Microfilm 6, Reel 5061)
  - Washington Square News, September 1984-May 1986 (Box Microfilm 6, Reel 5062)
  - Washington Square News, 1986-1987 (Box Microfilm 3)
  - Washington Square News, Summer 1987 (Box Microfilm 3, Reel 8106)
- Print copies
  - Washington Square Daily News, September 20, 1973-May 14, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Washington Square News, September 19, 1974-December 8, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Washington Square News, December 11, 1974-May 10, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Washington Square News, September 16, 1976-March 8, 1978 (Box 3)
  - Washington Square News, March 13, 1978-May 16, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Washington Square News, September 20, 1979-February 11, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Washington Square News, February 18, 1981-April 19, 1982 (Box 6)
  - Washington Square News, April 21, 1982-November 30, 1983 (Box 7)
  - Washington Square News, December 7, 1983-April 17, 1985 (Box 8)
  - Washington Square News, April 22, 1985-April 9, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Washington Square News, September 1986-April 17, 1987 (Box 10)
  - Washington Square News, April 14, 1986-April 2, 1987 (Box 11)
  - Washington Square News, April 29, 1987-November 4, 1987 (Box 12)
  - Washington Square News, November 4, 1987-April 25, 1988 (Box 13)
  - Washington Square News, April 27, 1988-November 2, 1988 (Box 14)
  - Washington Square News, November 7, 1988-February 22, 1989 (Box 15)
  - Washington Square News, January 24, 1990-March 5, 1990 (Box 16)
  - Washington Square News, March 7, 1990-November 1, 1990 (Box 17)
  - Washington Square News, November 2, 1990-March 8, 1991 (Box 18)
  - Washington Square News, March 19, 1991-November 11, 1991 (Box 19)
  - Washington Square News, November 13, 1991-May 4, 1992 (Box 20)
  - Washington Square News, August 31, 1992-October 5, 1993 (Box 21)
  - Washington Square News, October 6, 1993-May 2, 1994 (Box 22)
  - Washington Square News, September 28, 1994-April 13, 1995 (Box 23)
  - Washington Square News, April 14, 1995-November 8, 1995 (Box 24)
  - Washington Square News, November 9, 1995-March 6, 1996 (Box 25)
  - Washington Square News, March 18, 1996-September 27, 1996 (Box 26)
  - Washington Square News, September 30, 1996-December 5, 1996 (Box 27)
  - Washington Square News, December 9, 1996-April 23, 1997 (Box 28)
  - Washington Square News, April 24, 1997-November 20, 1997 (Box 29)
  - Washington Square News, November 24, 1997-May 5, 1998 (Box 30)
  - Washington Square News, August 31, 1998-October 25, 1999 (Box 31)
  - Washington Square News, October 26, 1999-May 11, 2000 (Box 32)
  - Washington Square News, August 28, 2000-January 30, 2001 (Box 33)
  - Washington Square News, January 31, 2001-December 9, 2001 (Box 34)
  - Washington Square News, January 23, 2002-November 25, 2002 (Box 35)
  - Washington Square News, December 2, 2002-November 18, 2003 (Box 36)
  - Washington Square News, November 24, 2003-April 26, 2004, April 4, 2013, January 26, 2015-March 11, 2015 (Box 37)
  - Washington Square News, March 12, 2015-January 25, 2015 (Box 38)
  - Washington Square News, February 1, 2016-May 9, 2017 (Box 39)
- Bound print copies
  - Washington Square News, September 24, 1984-December 19, 1984 (Volume Bound 1984)
  - Washington Square News, February 11, 1985-May 6, 1985 (Volume Bound February-May 1985)
  - Washington Square News, September 18, 1985-December 18, 1985 (Volume Bound September-December 1985)
  - Washington Square News, January 15, 1986-May 19, 1986 (Volume Bound January-May 1986)
  - Washington Square News, November 10, 1986-December 10, 1986 (Volume Bound November-December 1986)
  - Washington Square News, September 12, 1988-December 12, 1988 (Volume Bound September-December 1988)
  - Washington Square News, September 6, 1989-November 8, 1989 (Volume Bound September-November 1989)
  - Washington Square News, January 24, 1990-April 25, 1990 (Volume Bound January-April 1990)
  - Washington Square News, September 4, 1990-December 12, 1990 (Volume Bound September-December 1990)
  - Washington Square News, January 21, 1991-May 3, 1991 (Volume Bound January-May 1991)
  - Washington Square News, January 28, 1992-April 27, 1992 (Volume Bound January-April 1992)
  - Washington Square News, February 4, 1993-April 28, 1993 (Volume Bound February-April 1993)
  - Washington Square News, August 30, 1993-December 14, 1993 (Volume Bound August-December 1993)
  - Washington Square News, January 20, 1994-April 28, 1994 (Volume Bound January-April 1994)
  - Washington Square News (2 copies), September 1, 1994-December 12, 1994 (Volume Bound September-December 1994)
  - Washington Square News, January 23, 1995-May 18, 1995 (Volume Bound January-May 1995)
  - Washington Square News, August 31, 1995-December 11, 1995 (Volume Bound August-December 1995)
  - Washington Square News (2 copies), January 22, 1996-May 16, 1996 (Volume Bound January-May 1996)
  - Washington Square News, September 4, 1996-December 11, 1996 (Volume Bound September-December 1996)
  - Washington Square News, January 23, 1997-May 15, 1997 (Volume Bound January-May 1997)
  - Washington Square News, August 26, 1997-December 10, 1997 (Volume Bound August-December 1997)
  - Washington Square News, January 21, 1998-May 14, 1998 (Volume Bound January-May 1998)
  - Washington Square News, August 31, 1998-December 13, 1998 (Volume Bound August-December 1998)
  - Washington Square News, Jan. 20, 1999-May 13, 1999 (Volume Bound January-May 1999)
  - Washington Square News, Aug. 30, 1999-Dec. 10, 1999 (Volume Bound August-December 1999)
  - Washington Square News, January 19, 2000-April 30, 2000 (Volume Bound January-April 2000)
  - Washington Square News, Aug. 28, 2000-Dec. 10, 2000 (Volume Bound August-December 2000)
  - Washington Square News, Jan. 17, 2001-May 9, 2001 (Volume Bound January-May 2001)
  - Washington Square News, August 27, 2001-December 9, 2001 (Volume Bound August-December 2001)
  - Washington Square News, Jan. 23, 2002-May 13, 2002 (Volume Bound January-May 2002)
  - Washington Square News, Aug. 26, 2002-Dec. 6, 2002 (Volume Bound August-December 2002)
  - Washington Square News, Jan. 22, 2003-June 30, 2003 (Volume Bound January-June 2003)
  - Washington Square News, August 25, 2003-December 5, 2003 (Volume Bound August-December 2003)
  - Washington Square News, January 21, 2004-June 28, 2004 (Volume Bound January-June 2004)
  - Washington Square News, August 30, 2005-December 9, 2005 (Volume Bound August-December 2005)
  - Washington Square News, Jan. 17, 2006-June 26, 2006 (Volume Bound January-June 2006)
  - Washington Square News (2 copies), August 27, 2007-December 7, 2007 (Volume Bound August-December 2007)
  - Washington Square News, January 22, 2008-June 30, 2008 (Volume Bound January-June 2008)
  - Washington Square News, Fall 2008 (Volume Bound Fall 2008)
  - Washington Square News, Fall 2009 (Volume Bound Fall 2009)
  - Washington Square News, Spring 2009 (Volume Bound Spring 2009)
  - Washington Square News, Fall 2010 (Volume Bound Fall 2010)
  - Washington Square News, Spring 2010 (Volume Bound Spring 2010)
  - Washington Square News, Fall 2011 (Volume Bound Fall 2011)
  - Washington Square News (2 copies), Spring 2011 (Volume Bound Spring 2011)
  - Washington Square News, Spring 2012 (Volume Bound Spring 2012)
  - Washington Square News, Fall 2013 (Volume Bound Fall 2013)
- The Village Angle Magazine
  Scope and Contents
  The Village Angle was an arts and culture magazine published by the Washington Square News in the 1980s.
  - The Village Angle Magazine, February 23, 1983-May 16, 1988 (Box 42)